http://www.halotrust.org/privacy-policy/

This site uses cookies. By continuing to browse the site you are agreeing to our use of cookies.
Read our Cookies Policy.
Managing weapons & ammunition
Physical security and stockpile management (PSSM)
1               Privacy Policy
This Privacy Policy applies to you if you live in the EU or if you make a donation to HALO UK. If you are a US citizen and you make a donation to HALO USA, then this Privacy Policy will not apply to you and your personal data will be processed by HALO USA in accordance with Privacy Policy (US).
The HALO Trust is a private company limited by guarantee registered in England and Wales under company number 02228587. We are a registered charity and our registration number with the Charity Commission for England and Wales is 1001813 and with the Office of the Scottish Charity Regulator is SC037870. Our main trading address is Carronfoot, Thornhill, Dumfries DG3 5BF.
The HALO Trust is committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. If you have any queries about this Policy or how we use your personal information, please contact us using the details at Contact Us.
This policy (together with our Terms of Use and any other documents referred to in it) sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us.  Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it. By visiting https://www.halotrust.org/ you are accepting and consenting to the practices described in this policy.
For the purpose of the Data Protection Act 1998 and the General Data Protection Regulation whichever may be in force in England and Wales from time to time (the Act), the data controller is The HALO Trust.
1.1           Your consent
We require your express consent to use your information for certain purposes. By positively accepting this privacy policy, you consent to our processing such information in accordance with the purposes and provisions of this Privacy Policy, in particular you consent to us contacting you including for marketing and fundraising purposes in accordance with the preference you have notified to us.
1.2           How do we collect information?
We obtain personal information from you when you use our website, enquire about our activities, register with us, send or receive an email, ask a question or otherwise provide us with personal information.
We may also receive information about you from third parties, for example from other charities, or from individuals or third party organisations who share our interests and may introduce you to us.
1.3            What information do we collect?
We collect personal data as defined by the Act. The personal information we collect might include name, date of birth, email address, postal address, and telephone number. We record your requests for information and any feedback we receive from you. We may also collect technical information relating to your use of our website, including your browser type or the Internet Protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the internet.
We may collect information about you which you have either voluntarily made available, or which is already in the public domain.
We want to ensure that your personal information is accurate and up to date. If any of the information that you have provided us with changes, for example if you change your email address, name, payment details, or if you wish to cancel your registration, please let us know using the contact details at the end of this policy.
We also gather general information about the use of our website, such as which pages users visit most often and which services, events or facilities are of most interest. We may also track which pages users visit when they click on links in emails. We may use this information to personalise the way our website is presented when users visit, to make improvements to our website and to ensure we provide the best service for users. Wherever possible we use aggregated or anonymous information which does not identify individual visitors to our website.
1.4           How do we use this information?
We will use your personal information:
to promote the aims of The HALO Trust;
to provide you with our newsletter, campaign details or other information you have requested;
to provide you with information about future events and campaigns we think may be of interest to you, including third party events;
for administration purposes; to notify you about changes to our services; as part of our efforts to keep our site safe and secure; and to ensure that content from our site is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer; and
for statistical analysis.
We will only use your personal information for electronic marketing purposes if we are allowed to do this by law or if we have your consent.  If you agree to us providing you with marketing information, you can always opt out at a later date.  If you would rather not receive marketing material from us, please let us know at any time using the contact details at Contact Us or by unsubscribing.
We may analyse the personal information we collect for the purpose of creating the best relationship with you and so that we can contact you in the most appropriate way and with the most relevant information.
Where relevant, we may also assess your personal information for the purposes of fraud and credit risk reduction.
If you enter your personal details in one of our online forms, we may use this information to contact you to see if we can help with any problems you might be experiencing with the form or with our website, even before you have submitted the form.
1.5           Do we share your information with anyone else?
We share your personal information with The HALO Trust (USA), Inc. We may need to provide your information to our contractors, suppliers and professional advisers who provide services on our behalf, to the extent necessary to enable you to receive those services.
If you choose to donate in GBP your donation will be processed in the United Kingdom.
If you choose to donate in USD your donation will be processed in the United States of America.
If you make a payment or donation to us we will need to share your information with our payment processor. By paying via our payment processor you agree to accept their terms and conditions for the use of their services, including their privacy policy. We suggest that you read their privacy policy when using their service as we are not responsible for data you share with them.
We may also need to disclose your information if required to do so by law or as expressly permitted under the Act.
We may need to share your information with our service providers, associated organisations and agents for the purposes described above.
Our site may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks, advertisers and affiliates.  If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies.  Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.
1.6           How do we protect personal information?
We use a secure service when you make a donation through our website, via a virtual gateway operated by Donorbox. Payments are collected by Stripe, which is Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard compliant. We suggest that you read their terms and conditions when using their service to make a payment as we are not responsible for data you share with them.
We take appropriate measures to ensure that the information disclosed to us is kept secure, accurate and up to date and kept only for so long as is necessary for the purposes for which it is used. However, you should be aware that the use of the Internet is not entirely secure and although we will do our best to protect your personal data we cannot guarantee the security or integrity of any personal information which is transferred from you or to you via the Internet. Any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features such as encryption to try to prevent unauthorised access.
1.7           Your Rights
You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. You also have the right to ask for a copy of the information we hold about you (for which we may charge a fee if permitted by law).
You may ask us, or we may ask you, to rectify information you or we think is inaccurate, and you may also ask us to remove information which is inaccurate. If you inform us that your personal data is inaccurate, we will inform relevant third parties with whom we have shared your data so they may update their own records. You have a right to obtain your personal data from us and reuse it for your own purposes, perhaps for another service, without hindering the usability of the data. This will only apply when we are automatically processing your data for the performance of a contract.
You have a right to seek the erasure of your data (often referred to as the ‘right to be forgotten’). You may wish to exercise this right for any reason, for example where it is no longer necessary for us to continue holding or processing your personal data you may withdraw your consent. You should note that we are entitled to and reserve the right to retain your data for statistical purposes.
You have a right to prevent us from processing your data for the purposes of marketing.
If you would like to exercise any of your rights above, please let us know using the contact details at the end of this policy. We will act in accordance with your instructions as soon as reasonably possible and there will be no charge.
1.8           Cookies
Our website uses cookies to distinguish you from other users of our website. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse our website and also allows us to improve our site. For detailed information on the cookies we use and the purposes for which we use them see our Cookie Policy.
1.9           Changes to this policy
Any changes we may make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail. Please check back frequently to see any updates or changes to our privacy policy. By continuing to use our website you will be deemed to have accepted such changes.
This Privacy Policy was last amended in August 2017.
Useful Info
Policies & Safeguarding
Knowledge sharing
FAQs
Get Involved
Donate
Raise money
Get in touch
CARRONFOOT, THORNHILL, DUMFRIES, DG3 5BF
The HALO Trust is a company limited by guarantee. Registered in England No. 2228587. Registered Charity No. 1001813 and (in Scotland) SC037870. Registered Office: One Bartholomew Close, Barts Square, London EC1A 7BL
The HALO Trust (USA), Inc. is a 501(c)(3) not-for-profit organization US Federal Tax ID Number 52-2158152Office: 1730 Rhode Island Ave NW, Suite 206, Washington, DC 20036
By registering for our updates, or making a donation to us, you expressly agree to your information being used by The HALO Trust and The HALO Trust (USA), Inc. in accordance with our privacy protection policy. You can unsubscribe at any time.
×
Modal title
